Drew Drew 別再說了
Drew. Drew,justjust stop.
我明白 所以Allison才會和你在一起
I get it. That's why allison is with you.
老天 我正在解決
Oh,god. I am dealing with it.
Ben!
是你帶走她的 記得嗎?
Well,you took her from me,remember?
Ben 你怎麼還沒交電費
Ben,i thought you paid the bill.
你在幹什麼?
What are you doing?
Ben?
再放大 圖像就會變形了
Any closer and the image will distort.
Jack怎麼樣?
How is jack?
很聰明 是個好孩子 讓我們很欣慰
He's real smart. Had us in tears. Great kid.
Haley呢?
Haley?
實話說 我們準備送他們到暫住點
To be honest,we're moving them to a halfway house.
我以為你找到固定住所了
I thought you had found a permanent location.
Haley給她媽媽打了幾個電話
Haley made a number of phone calls to her mother.
問題不大 但安全起見 我們不得不轉移
It's all good, but to be safe, we have to move them.
Sam 謝謝你
Sam,thank you.
我保證 他們絕不會受到傷害
I promise you, no harm will come to them.
你只要全心對付Foyet
You just concentrate on getting foyet.
生日快樂 夥計
Happy birthday,buddy.
有時間嗎?
You got a second?
什麼事?
Sure,what is it?
有新案子
A case just came in.
我一會就來
I'll be right there.
其實 我有話跟你說
Actually, I need to talk to you.
案子是在長島的康梅克市 你家鄉
It's on commack,long island. That's your home town.
對 要是可以 我想留下來
Yeah. And if it's ok, i'd rather stay behind.
為什麼?
Why?
30年前離開那兒時  我的生活與現在截然不同
It was a different life, one I left 30 years ago.
我還不想回去 這樣...
I'm in no hurry to go back. Well...
要是放在平常 我就答應了 但是看看這個
Any other day, i'd say stay, but I just became aware of this.
什麼情況?
What have we got?
昨晚Ben Vanderwaal在長島的 康梅克市 被近距離槍殺
Ben vanderwaal was killed in commack,long island, last night, shot at close range,
心臟和頭部各中一槍 .22口徑彈殼
once in the heart, once in the head, . 22 caliber shell.
發現了他妻子Heather的頭髮和血跡
They found hair and blood traces from ben vanderwaal's wife heather.
沒發現Heather?
But not heather?
沒有 她失蹤了 估計已死亡
No,she's still missing, presumed dead.
子彈口徑與位置和前兩位受害者吻合
The caliber and placement of the bullets match that of two previous victims.
第一位 Rita Haslat
The first,rita haslat.
8個月前 她在新澤西州的家堨Ⅹ
8 months ago she went missing from her home in new jersey.
4周後 在垃圾桶箱被發現
4 weeks later,she was found in a trash bin.
她在3周內瘦成了這副樣子?
She went from that to this in under 3 weeks?
絕對是人為故意造成的
She's totally emaciated.
手腕和腳踝上的痕跡 顯示她曾被捆綁的
Ligature marks on her wrists and ankles indicate she was constrained.
心臟和頭部各中一槍  和Vanderwaal相同
One in the heart, one in the headsame as vanderwaal.
聽起來更像是處決
Sounds more like an execution.
為什麼要在Vanderwaal死後 砍掉他的手呢?
Then why cut off vanderwaal's hands postmortem?
第三名受害者呢?
What about the third victim?
Bill Levington 他的體征顯然改變了
Bill levington. His appearance was certainly altered.
他的生殖器不見了
His genitals were missing.
雖然每案具體殘害方法不同 但顯然已出現個性簽名
Though the method of mutilation is different in each crime, clearly there's a signature.
問題是 個性簽名是什麼?
The question is,what?
20分鐘後起飛 這什麼?
Wheelsup in 20 minutes. What's this?
你說你可以出勤了 謊話
You told me you were cleared to travel. You lied.
淘氣哦 不是 我沒有
Naughty boy. Uh,no,i didn't.
我是個博士 所以嚴格說來不算謊話
I am a doctor,so technically, I wasn't a lie.
那是什麼?
What was it,then?
不同意見
Second opinion.
你現在歸我管了
You're my bitch now.
犯罪心理 第五季 第3集 清算
Criminal Minds Season06 Episode03 Reckoner
"正義缺少武力是無能
"justice without force is powerless.
武力缺少正義是暴政"
Force without justice is tyrannical."
法國哲學家帕斯卡
blaise pascal.
Ben Vanderwaal的雙手被砍掉了
In the ben vanderwaal case, his hands were taken.
Bill Levington被除去生殖器
Uh,bill levington, his genitals.
只有Rita Haslat在處決前 遭到了飢餓和虐待
Only in the rita haslat case she was starved and tortured, then executed,
而且死後沒有截肢
and there's no sign of postmortem mutilation.
他為什麼要帶走Heather Vanderwaal 而不是簡單地殺了她?
Why would he take heather vanderwaal and not simply kill her?
也許他還沒下手 她還活著
Maybe he hasn't and she's still alive.
目前唯一明確的是作案手法 顯示罪犯注重效率 實用
The only thing concrete is the m.O., which depicts an efficient nononsense murderer.
我們要找出不同殘害行為 對不明疑犯意味著什麼
Well,then we need to figure out what each act of mutilation means to the unsub.
或者是對受害者
Or to the victim.
長島 康梅克市 Vanderwaal 家
發現現場時基本就這樣 沒有強行闖入的痕跡
It's pretty much how we found it. There's no signs of forced entry.
資料上說Heather Vanderwaal 有個女兒 她現在在哪?
It says in the file that heather vanderwaal has a daughter. Where is she?
搬去聖地亞哥和生父一起生活了
She moved to san diego to live with her real father.
Ben和Heather結婚只有幾年
Ben and heather vanderwaal have only been married a couple of years.
Heather進門 放下購物袋  手機 鑰匙 但沒有放下外套
So heather came in, she dropped her shopping bags, her cell phone,and her keys, but not her coat.
她開燈
She turns on the lights.
但沒亮 因為電話和電力都被切斷了
But they didn't work, because the phone and the electricity were cut.
這房間有東西引起了她的注意
Something in this room attracted her attention.
這是什麼?
What is it?
血跡堛漲L子像是相機的三腳架
Marks in the blood look like a camera tripod.
連環殺手 尤其是性施虐狂  經常會拍下他們的殺戮
Serial killers, especially sexual sadists, often document their kill.
不過性施虐者一般會在 受害人活著的時候折磨他們
But sexual sadists usually torture their victims while they're still alive.
至今依然沒有發現衝突的DNA?
You still didn't find any conflicting dna?
沒有 指紋 纖維 什麼都沒有
No. No prints, no fibers,nothing.
沒有人聽見槍聲嗎? 沒
Nobody heard any shots? No.
抱歉
Oh,excuse me.
喂 知道了
Yeah? All right.
半小時發現Heather Vanderwaal 走在大街上
Heather vanderwaal was just found wandering the streets half hour ago.
現在在Brookside綜合醫院
She's at brookside general.
讓JJ過去
Get jj over there.
這麼老練的殺手不會無故留下活口
A killer this sophisticated doesn't leave a living witness without a reason.
Heather 我是Jareau探員
Heather,my name is agent jareau.
我有幾個問題想問你
I have some questions for you.
你回到家 想開燈 但燈沒有亮
So you came home, you tried to turn the lights on, but they didn't work.
接下來你做了什麼?
What did you do next?
我看見光 閃光燈
I saw a light. A flash.
我打開門 Ben在堶 被綁在椅子上
I opened the door, and ben was there, tied to a chair.
我覺得他已經死了
I think he was dead.
然後閃光燈又亮了
There was another flash.
我眼前黑了一陣
It blinded me for a moment.
看見襲擊你的人了嗎? 沒有
Did you see your attacker? No.
他有沒有說什麼? 沒
Did he say anything? No.
我聽見有聲音
I heard this noise.
什麼聲音?
What kind of noise?
鋸東西
Sawing.
我親眼看他切下Ben的手
I watched him cut off ben's hand.
他為什麼不殺了我?
Why didn't he kill me?
抱歉
Excuse me.
Garcia
Garcia.
找到一些Heather Vanderwaal的資料
We've been getting to know heather vanderwaal.
我說不出她最喜歡披頭士堛瑤 但我知道她過得極其不開心
I can't tell you her favorite beatle, but I can tell you she was living la vida unhappy.
你發現了什麼?
What did you find?
她前夫在學期中把女兒Allison接走了
Her exhusband took her daughter allison out of school midterm.
然後Heather在6天前 開了張 5千美元的支票到"Lewis Bell&Peter"
After that,heather cut a check for $5,000 to a place called lewis,bell,& peters 6 days ago.
法律事務所? 婚姻家庭法
Law firm? Family law.
謝了
Thanks.
Vanderwaal夫人
Mrs. Vanderwaal...
你的女兒在學期中退學了?
At midterm you moved your daughter out of school?
對
Yes,i did.
之後 你申請和Ben離婚
After that,you filed for divorce from ben.
那個男人放過你是有原因的
This man left you alive for a reason.
我需要知道這兩件事是否有聯繫
I need to know if these two things are connected.
幾個月前 我在Ben手機 發現了一張Allison的照片
A few months ago, I found a picture of allison on ben's phone.
你女兒
Your daughter.
她沒有穿衣服
She was naked.
在哪堜蝒? 我不知道
Where was it taken? I couldn't tell.
你問過他嗎? 問了
Did you confront him? Yes.
他說是Allison錯發給他的
He claimed that allison sent it to him by mistake.
她原本是想發給她同學的
She meant to send it to another student at her school.
叫性短信
It's called sexting.
Allison怎麼說?
What did allison say?
她說是Ben拍的 但她愛撒謊
She said ben took it, but sheshe lies.
Allison經常撒謊
Allison,she's a liar.
她給我們惹了很多麻煩
She caused us a lot of trouble,you know?
可這件事她沒說謊 對嗎?
She wasn't lying about this, though,was she?
沒有
No.
手的切除手法並不專業
The hand removal is less than surgical.
他用的是普通雙倍齒的鋸子
He used a basic doubletoothed saw.
所以 我們要找的人沒有醫學背景
So,the guy we're looking for has no medical training.
反正不是我這種的
Not the kind i've had.
一槍在心臟 一槍在頭部 近距離射擊
One in the heart, one in the brain,close range.
第二槍就在耳朵後面
The second one was right up behind the ear.
槍擊殘留物呢?
How about gunshot residue?
少的可憐
Surprisingly little.
也許因為殺手用的是.22
Maybe it's because the killer was using a .22
口徑小 殘留物就少
Small caliber,small discharge.
怎麼了?
What is it?
彈道測試結果沒有找到 與子彈匹配的槍支
Ballistics can't match the bullets to a gun.
子彈上沒有膛線痕跡
There were no rifling marks on the bullet.
對此就只有一個解釋
There's only one explanation for that.
要真有人想殺Ben Vanderwaal  那就是Heather的前夫了
Well,if anyone had a motive to kill ben vanderwaal, it was heather's exhusband.
他在聖地亞哥  而且同前兩名受害人沒有聯繫
But he was in san diego, and he has no connection to the other two victims.
David Rossi 終於見到您了
David rossi, we finally get to meet.
我是Gil Hardesty探長  有您來協助真是太榮幸了
Detective gil hardesty. Very,very nice to have you with us.
Morgan 你發現了什麼?
Morgan, what did you find?
所有案子堛.22口徑子彈 都沒有膛線痕跡
In all cases, the . 22 caliber bullets had no rifling marks.
槍管缺少膛線的推動  子彈的速度一定很慢
And without the barrel being rifled, the bullets would have very little velocity.
他需要近距離直接射擊受害人 JJ
He would have to shoot his victim pointblank. Jj.
這人用的是自製手槍 要是知道方法的話
This guy's using a zip gun.Now,if you know what you're doing,
一段水管或者兒童車打氣筒 就能改製成一把槍
a piece of plumbing or a kid's bicycle pump can be turned into a gun.
一槍在心臟 一槍在頭部
One in the heart, one in the head.
子彈無法追蹤 毫無疑問
Untraceable,expandable bullets tell me without question,
這些謀殺絕對是職業手法 職業殺手干的?
all of these kills were strictly business. A hitman?
那些死後截肢怎麼說?
What about the postmortem mutilation?
僱傭協議也可能會有額外要求
A contract sometimes includes extras.
相機為的不是性滿足  而是目標死亡的證據
The camera is not for sexual gratification, it's for proof of death.
那我們要找的是兩個人嗎?
So we could be looking for two people?
有可能 可能更多 抱歉
Maybe. Maybe more. Excuse me.
也許我可以找找舊相識幫忙 不過我要單獨行動
I may be able to hit on some old contacts, but i'll need to do it alone.
相識? 我們會想知道嗎?
Contacts? Do we want to know?
最好別
Best not.
我們5:30才開門
We don't open till 5:30.
我要找那件外套的主人
I'm looking for the owner of that coat.
是嗎?
Is that right?
帶了這個可沒門
Not with that you're not.
去檢查前後門
Check out the front and back.
你是承認是警察 還是把命擱在這兒?
You're either a dead man or a cop. Which one is it?
現在 我只是一個老朋友
Right now i'm just an old friend.
當上聯邦探員那天 你就放棄這權利了
You gave up that right the day you became a fed.
Ray?
David
David.
我以為你退休在家寫書呢?
I thought you retired. Writing books?
要我怎麼說呢 Ray?
What can I tell you,ray?
有些習慣是很難改的
Some habits are hard to break.
每天早上我都做這該死的字謎
I try this damn puzzle every morning.
一點也沒進步
Never gets any easier.
"彈坑創造者"
"crater creator."
我有個同事 那小子5分鐘就能解決
you know, I work with a kid who can solve this whole thing in 5 minutes.
他肯定比咱倆加起來都聰明
He must be smarter than both of us.
那是肯定的
That's for sure.
多久沒見了 30年? 33年
So what's it been, 30 years? 33.
我還以為 最不濟也能在 Emma的葬禮上看到你
You know,i thought at the very least I would see you at emma's funeral.
我...想請你幫個忙
I,um... Need to ask you a favor.
她愛的並不比你少
She loved you as much as you loved her.
野心真是害人不淺 是吧?
Hey,ambition's a bitch, ain't it?
我不是來和你聊Emma的
I'm not here to talk about emma.
那你來這幹嘛?
What are you here to talk about?
新聞你看了? 你覺得我和那事有關?
You've read the news? You think I got something to do with that?
你還是老老實實寫書吧
You should stick to writing books.
兇手手法很有特點
This guy is real specific.
用自製小手槍殺人 再附帶折磨
He uses a zip gun and then throws in extras.
你是個聰明人 回這來太蠢了
For a smart guy, your coming back here was a real dumb move.
那Sean不就更蠢了
Not as dumb as the one that sean made.
他因為運輸軍火受審 無疑是你的替罪羊
He's on trial for the transportation of weapons, no doubt for you.
還有你那詐騙腐敗組織集團犯罪呢?
And what about the rico beef hanging over your head?
你幫了我 就等於協助聯邦調查
You help me, and you'll be assisting a federal investigation.
那就能讓我的名聲好起來了?
And what exactly is that gonna do for my reputation?
如果你不幫 可就沒名聲可言了
If you don't, you may not have one to protect.
我們集團犯罪部門 就快讓你永遠歇業了
Our organized crime unit is very close to shutting you down permanently.
繼續說
Keep talking.
鋸斷手臂和Rita Haslat被發現時 的情況一樣目的明確
The removal of the hands is as specific as rita haslat's condition was when she was found.
和Bill Levington生殖器被割除也一樣
Just as specific as the removal of bill levington's genitals.
不明嫌犯想利用切除傳達某種訊息
There's a message in the mutilations the unsub wants us to know.
我這兒有點東西可能有用
I got something here that might help us with
嚴格來說 是我們有點東西可能有用
technically,we have something here that might help with that.
Bill Levington參與多宗強姦案  均涉及未成年人 但從未受審
Bill levington was involved in a serial rape case, all involving minors, and it never went to trial.
Rita Haslat呢?
Rita haslat?
以前是社工
A former social worker,
因為重大失職 被兒童與家庭服務部門解雇
attained said former status when she was fired from the dcfs for gross negligence.
她經手的一個案例中 一名七歲男童被餓死
In one of her cases, a 7yearold boy starved to death.
也就解釋了Haslat被發現時 為什麼那麼消瘦
Which explains why haslat was so emaciated when she was found.
所有受害者都涉及兒童案件的話 我們就找到聯繫了
If all the victims were indicated in crimes against children, then we've found a connection.
不明嫌犯能知曉受害人的罪行  可能從事司法行業
One of the unsubs has access to the crimes of the victims and probably works in the justice system.
Garcia? 這就查
Garcia? On it.
好了 我們發現受害人的共同點了
All right,well, we know what the victims have in common,
只需找出與他們都有聯繫的人
we just need to find out who they have in common.
等等 社工和涉嫌強姦案是有記錄的
Wait. This social worker and the suspected rape case, those were matters of record.
Ben Vanderwaal和她繼女的事可沒有
Ben vanderwaal's relationship with his stepdaughter is not.
除非那個女孩告訴了別人
Unless the stepdaughter told someone else.
我打給Rossi
I'll call rossi.
我把那女孩帶過來
I'll have the daughter brought in.
三個案子都涉及兒童?
And all 3 crimes were against children?
好 謝謝了 Prentiss
Ok. Thanks,prentiss.
古巴的 毫無疑問
Cuban,no doubt.
走私貨?
Contraband?
有些法律就是不公正的
Some laws are just plain unjust.
那三個人都傷害過小孩
You know,those 3 individuals messed with kids.
完全是罪有應得
They got what they deserve.
那得看你怎麼定義公正了
That all depends on your definition of justice.
跟咱年輕時一樣
It's the same as when we were kids.
為了生存 就得不擇手段
You do what you gotta do to survive.
那這個人呢?
What about this guy?
這手法只能出自一個人
Yeah. There's only one guy that's this specific.
誰?
Name?
Bosola
Bosola.
我昨晚跟Heather通過話
I spoke to heather last night.
我早知道有事不對勁 可這也...你怎麼不告訴我呢?
I knew for a long time something was off,but thiswhy didn't you tell me?
Sandweiss先生 Allison可是受害者
Mr. Sandweiss, allison is the victim here.
我只想讓她告訴我事實 哪怕就一次
I just want to know the truth from her, for once.
我說了 我不知道他們在說什麼
I told you, I don't know what they're talking about.
Allison 我們有你繼父給你拍的照片
Allison,we have the pictures your stepfather took of you.
Allison...
他總是比媽媽早到家
He was always home before mom.
一開始我們只是說說話
We just talked at first.
為什麼不和你媽媽說?
Why didn't you tell your mom?
我知道她會告訴爸爸  他總說誰要敢碰我就宰了誰
I knew she'd tell dad, and he always said he'd kill anyone who laid a hand on me.
他碰你了嗎?
And did he?
他幹這行多久了?
How long has he been operating?
20年了 他神出鬼沒的
20 years. He's a ghost.
我聽過這名字 Bosola
I've heard that name. Bosola.
是一齣戲劇堛漕丹
He's a character in a play.
詹姆斯時期悲劇 瑪爾菲女公爵
Jacobean tragedy called the duchess of malfi.
Bosola殘忍地殺害了女公爵
Bosola brutally slays the duchess.
不然就不能稱其為悲劇了
It wouldn't be a tragedy if he didn't.
本地人?
Is he local?
我不在乎什麼集團犯罪案
I don't care about the rico beef.
Sean會怎麼樣?
What about sean?
聯邦監獄 兩年
Federal prison,out in 2.
好吧
All right.
今晚我帶Bosola來
I'll bring you bosola tonight.
你最好帶海軍陸戰隊過來
You better bring the marine corps.
Allison 你有沒有和別人 說過你繼父的事?
Allison,did you ever tell anyone about what your stepfather was doing?
我和治療醫師說過
I told my therapist.
他說我是為了引起注意
He said I act out because I crave attention.
對不起 爸爸
I'm so sorry,daddy.
你沒有做錯什麼
You have nothing to be sorry for.
我們想知道他是誰 你的治療醫師
We need his name, please. Your therapist.
Jerry Sorum
Jerry sorum.
我是犯罪嫌疑人?
Am I a suspect?
還不是 Sorum先生
Not yet,mr. Sorum.
你給Allison的專業看法是什麼?
What is your professional opinion of allison?
你指繼父是否性虐待她? 毫無疑問
You mean was she sexually abused by her stepfather? No question.
你上報了? 是的
And you reported it. Of course.
上報給警方? 當然了
To the police? Absolutely.
他們怎麼處理的?
How far did they take it?
按州法律審核了
They had it reviewed by the state.
警方給她錄口供了嗎?
Did the police interview her?
他們來過我的辦公室 Allison不想扯上關係 案子就結了
They came to my office. Allison wanted nothing to do with it. Case closed.
就跟國家每年380,000例 上報的虐待兒童案件一樣
Just like the 380,000 cases of child abuse reported in this country each year.
只有不到百分之一能開庭審判
Less than one percent gets to trial.
是不是讓你很想討回公道?
Does that make you want to even the odds?
每當聽孩子重述 都感覺那麼逼真
Every time I listen to a child vividly recount the most horrific acts of abuse
聽到他們本可信賴的人 父親 叔叔...
done at the hands of a father, an uncle,
對他們可怕的所作所為
someone they're supposed to trust...
我所能做的就是不讓自己崩潰
It's all I can do not to break down.
我也只能做到這樣
But that's all i'm capable of.
然後就只有依靠司法系統 像你一樣
After that,like you, I trust in the justice system.
Rossi 午夜 我的餐館見
Rossi. Midnight. My restaurant.
大多數人從來沒見過Bosola
Most people never meet bosola.
見過的也沒命見第二次
Those that do only ever meet him once.
如果被他察覺你是條子  我就和瑪爾菲女公爵一個下場了
If he smells a fed, i'm gonna end up like the duchess.
那就真的是悲劇了
Now,that would be a tragedy.
我從來沒說過不得體的話 對吧?
I've never said anything out of turn,ever,have i?
繼續
Go on.
您一直待我像親生兒子一樣
Always you've treated me like a son.
但我寧可坐牢 也不願你幫聯邦警察
今晚店堨薿
I'm closing the restaurant tonight.
你和其他人都休息
You and the boys take the night off.
我不能讓你一個人去幹
I can't let you do this alone.
我不是在幫警察
I'm not helping the feds.
我是幫一個老朋友
I'm helping an old friend.
晚安 下班吧
Good night. Go on.
燈光一暗 我們就進去
He dims the lights, we go in.
Jack今天四歲了? 是啊
So,uh,jack's what, 4 today? Yeah.
而我卻完全不知他身在何處
And I literally have no idea where he is.
他在安全的地方
He's safe.
我看到Prentiss和Morgan開走了  但車堥漕潃荓揚不是我們的人
I saw prentiss and morgan up the block, but the two agents in the sedan, they're not with us.
那是反監視人員 以防Foyet在監視我
That the counter surveillance in case foyet is watching me.
顯然 局婺g費短缺
For which,apparently, there's no more money.
是啊 我聽說了
Yeah,i heard.
有人給你打電話了?
Did somebody call you?
他們很關心 你怎麼說的?
They're concerned. What did you say?
跟我對你說的一樣  針對你就是針對我們大家
What i'm telling you. An attack against you is an attack against all of us.
你怎麼打來了? 沒事吧?
Why are you calling? You ok?
我希望你們外面的人能靠得住
I hope you got some good guys out there.
這傢伙可不是吃素的
This man is a mean son of a bitch.
我們都準備好了 他不會發覺的
We're all over. He's not gonna know what hit him.
那個孩子...很聰明的那個 能幫我個小忙嗎?
Hey,that kidthe,uh,smart oneI could use a little help.
Reid? Reid在
Reid? Reid here.
填字問題 五個字的 彈坑創造者
Crossword question. 10 letters. Crater creator.
五個字 彈坑創造者
10 letters, crater creator.
反正切函數
Arctangent.
聽見了嗎? 這姑娘真他媽聰明
Did you get that? Damn,she's smart.
你看到閃光了嗎?
Did you see thatflash?
看到了 他已經進去了
I saw that. He's already in there.
所有單位 上 上 上!
All units,go,go,go!
Morgan在外面巡查
Morgan's out canvassing the area.
整個地方都是警察
This whole place is swarming with cops.
我們掌控了街道 大樓 甚至屋頂
We had the streets, the building,even the damn roof covered.
他到底是怎麼躲過我們的?
How the hell did he get through us?
Garcia正在追查Finnegan的電話
Garcia traced finnegan's phone calls.
4:38時他打過一個預付電話  另一個就是11:41打給你的
He made one at 4:38 to a prepaid cell, another one to you at 11:41.
我們給了Bosola七個小時作準備
We gave bosola 7 hours to prepare.
我想他在我們之前就到了
I think he was here before we arrived.
然後他聽見Ray給我打電話  這都是我的錯
And he heard ray call me. This is all my fault.
現在他知道我們盯上他了 不只他知道了
Now he knows we're onto him. He's not the only one.
雇他的人也知道了
Whoever he works for does,too.
不明犯認為三位受害者犯下罪行 並以相應方式進行殘害
Each mutilation represents the crimes the unsubs believe these 3 individuals committed.
不明犯? 就是不明犯罪嫌疑人
Unsubs? Unknown subjects.
二人都為男性 不明犯甲  我們稱之為策劃者
2. Both male. Unsub "a" we're calling the planner.
他是刑事司法系統的工作人員
He works in the criminal justice system.
我們要找的可能是辯護律師 檢查官  法官 警察也有可能
We're looking at both defense and prosecution attorneys, judges,and even cops.
我們相信策劃者剛遭受重大生活挫折
We believe that the planner has experienced a devastating personal tragedy of some sort.
而且鑒於案情的複雜性
And because of the sophisticated nature of the scenario,
我們認為不名犯甲年齡在50到60歲
we believe unsub "a" is in his late 50s or 60s.
策劃者與實施者不明犯乙 很可能是通過司法系統認識的
The planner likely met unsub "b",the enforcer, within the court system.
後者被僱傭替天行道
He's been hired to carry out justice.
考慮僱傭價格不菲
Now,this type of justice does not come cheap.
策劃者應該有能力調動大量現金
So the planner has access to substantial cash.
他們未曾嘗試掩蓋截肢事實
Absolutely no attempt was made to hide the mutilation.
這表明策劃者要麼不在乎我們發現 要麼就是想讓我們發現
This suggests the planner either doesn't care what we find or he wants us to find it.
但是實施者就沒有這個用意了
Now,the enforcer, on the other hand, has no such intentions.
他應該是個全副武裝 且極度危險的人物
He should be considered armed and extremely dangerous.
多謝配合 好 幹活吧 大伙
Thank you. All right. Let's go,people.
最後幾筆酬勞已經打到你戶頭
All final payments have been made.
你好好完成任務 不必多問
I see no reason not to complete the tasks or to converse further.
很好 最後一個目標
Good.One last request
我希望你特別留意下Patton先生
I would like you to pay special attention to mr. Patton.
我在重點調查最近三個案子
I've concentrated on the last 3 cases.
有最新的檔案資料 很好
They've left the freshest eprints. Great.
不見得 長島法院經手的案子超過10萬
Not really. Over 100,000 cases pass through long island court.
都有誰看過那些資料?
Who had eyes on those files?
絕對數以千計了
Literally hundreds and hundreds of people.
那就改變策略 重點放在實施者身上
Change track. Focus on the enforcer.
長島過去十年中 涉及搶劫的謀殺審判
Mobrelated murder trials on long island the last 10 years.
我們找的是個職業殺手
We're looking for a hitman.
過去十年審理過93起搶劫案
Hey,there are 93 mob trials in the last 10 years.
被判有罪的都略過
Put aside any trials that resulted in a conviction.
找出未決審判和提訊案件
Weed out mistrials and arraignments.
還有19起
Uh,19.
那些案件的嫌疑人有沒有 是職業殺手或黑道打手的?
Were any of those on trial suspected of being hitmen or enforcers?
有3起 哇 哇 這個絕對是僥倖漏網
3whoa,whoa,whoa, this totally slipped the net.
Tony Mecacci 未決審判 但看看受害者
Tony mecaccihis case was judged a mistrial, but check out his suspected victim.
是.22口徑的吧? 一語中的
.22 caliber,right? Bull'seye.
交叉比對策劃者側寫和 這起審判所有相關人員
Crossmatch our profile of the planner against all those connected with this trial.
有公訴律師Garrett Daniels 法官Boyd Schuller 辯護律師Paul...
Let's seeprosecuting lawyer garrett daniels, judge boyd schuller, criminal defense lawyer paul
等等 你說有Schuller法官?
wait,wait. Did you say judge schuller?
對 這還有照片 怎麼了?
Yeah,here's a photo. What's wrong?
你認識他? 不認識 可他妻子我認識
Do you know him? No. But I knew his wife.
兩年前她下班開車回家  被一個酒後駕駛的司機撞死
2 years ago she was driving home from work and she was killed by a drunk driver.
這能算是重大挫折了
That could be the tragedy.
她是他畢生之愛 這可以肯定
She was the love of his life, that's for sure.
一年前 Schuller法官以健康為由離職
12 months ago,judge schuller took a leave of absence due to health issues.
他被診斷為癌癥晚期 還有六個月時間
He was diagnosed with terminal cancer. He has 6 months to live.
命案就是這時開始的
And that's when the killing started.
你不會真的認為法官... 是的 Schuller法官就是策劃者
You don't seriously think judgejudge schuller is the planner.Yes,i do.
符合側寫
Fits the profile.
Tony Mecacci很可能是殺手Bosola Bosola的資料都有什麼
And tony mecacci is most likely bosola the enforcer. What have you got on bosola?
最後一次審訊後銷聲匿跡
Uh,wofthe grid after his last trial.
JJ 發佈州境通告 向媒體公開Mecacci的照片
Jj,put out a statewide apb and release mecacci's photo to the media.
Schuller法官深受尊重
Judge schuller's a highlyrespected man.
我們不能就這麼抓他 說他是連環殺人犯
We can't just walk in there and accuse him of serial murder.
有必要的話 我就去找檢察長 並向首席大法官提出要求
Then i'll go to the attorney general and petition the chief justice if I have to.
也許不用
And maybe not.
我想你們在找我
I believe you're looking for me.
我們得聲明你所享有的權利
You know we have to advise you of your rights.
本人自證其罪 放棄憲法權利
I waive my constitutional rights against selfincrimination.
你進來時說"我想你們在找我"
When you walked in here, you said,"i believe you're looking for me."
我說得沒錯 時機把握天衣無縫
and I was right. Your timing was impeccable.
但你怎麼知道呢?
But how could you know that?
我知道你們不久就能找到我
I knew it wouldn't take you long to find me.
尤其我犯下這麼多罪
Not after what i've left behind.
那你不否認這一切?
So you don't deny any of this?
為什麼要否認? 你覺得是犯罪 我覺得是在伸張正義
Why would i? What you see as a crime, I see as justice.
Ray Finnegan是我的一個朋友
Ray finnegan was a friend of mine.
他是個罪犯
Ray finnegan was a criminal.
你交友應該更慎重些
You should choose your friends more wisely.
Ray出現在Emma的葬禮上 一定讓你很不安吧
It must have really thrown you when ray showed up at emma's funeral.
你怎麼知道我妻子的?
How do you know about my wife?
你還真不知道我是誰 是嗎?
You have absolutely no idea who I am,do you?
Ray告訴Rossi 只能見Bosola一次
Ray told rossi you only meet bosola once.
所以Schuller法官肯定給他名單了
So judge schuller had to have given him a list of names.
他無需跟他再見面 只要確信死亡後付錢就行了
He never needs to see him again, just make final payment on proof of death.
讓Garcia在一切沒結束前 黑進他的文檔 追蹤財務記錄
Have garcia hack into schuller's files and track his financial records before everything gets shut down.
查清楚他那方是否打過電話
And find out if his office made any calls.
打了 我幾小時跟他們通過話 告訴他們有兩名嫌疑人
They did. I spoke to them a few hours ago. I told them we had two suspects.
那他知道我們在查他了
So he knows we're onto him.
他是來拖延時間的
He came here to stall.
他的確有名單 還有受害者
He does have a list. There's more to come.
咱們接著說我來這的正事吧 怎麼?
Could we just get on with what I came here for? Why?
那樣Bosola就能繼續 執行你安排給他的活? 不
So bosola can go on and carry on whatever it is you asked of him to do? No.
你打電話給他 結束這一切
You call him and you end this.
就算可以 我也不打
Even if I could, I wouldn't.
Emma Louise Taylor 生於1958年7月4日
She was born emma louise taylor, 4th of july 1958.
這些資料你從哪都能查到
You could get that from anywhere.
6歲時 她父親John帶了一隻 黑白的流浪貓回家
When she was 6, her dad john brought him a black and white homeless kitten.
如果她認識你...
If she knew you...
她會告訴我的
Emma would have told me.
她給它取名叫奧斯卡 以王爾德的名字命名的
She named it oscar, after oscar wilde.
王爾德所有作品中 她最喜歡"理想丈夫"
And of all oscar wilde's work,she loved an ideal husband the most.
我不知道你怎麼這麼瞭解Emma
I don't know how you know all of this about emma
也不知道你想幹什麼 咱沒什麼好說的了
or what you hope to achieve, but we're done.
指控你們都清楚 告我吧
You know the charges. Charge me.
這些瘋狂舉動都因Emma的死而起嗎?
Is that what started all this insanityemma's death?
我宣誓保護司法系統 可35年來卻只能坐視其
What started all of this was the 35 years I had to sit and watch as the system
辜負應該保護的人們 一切因此而起
I swore an oath to protect failed the very people our justice system was meant to protect.
不知道Emma會怎麼看待這一切
I wonder what emma would make of all this.
名單上每個人都應受到公正審判
Every single person on that list deserves justice,
而他們卻逃脫了公正
and it's justice they managed to evade.
那麼你真有名單
So... You do have a list.
我說完了
I'm finished talking.
有很多雙向流量 也就是說有人不想讓我們進去
Ohoh,we've got gobs of twoway traffic going on, which means someone is trying to bounce us out.
Bosola收費很高 Schuller法官 肯定做了大額度交易轉賬
Ok,bosola didn't come cheap, so judge schuller had to have made some pretty substantial transactions.
有到開曼群島的電匯 到這就斷了
Got wire transfers to a cayman island bank and that's where the trace ends.
多少筆 多少錢?
How many,how much?
六月 每幾天就借記9999元 一共4次
June,he debits numerations of $9,999 every few days,total of 4,
停了幾個星期 然後完成最後一筆同額轉賬
he takes a break for a few weeks until he makes his final transaction for the same magic number.
低於一萬就不會被國稅局追查
Anything less than $10,000 keeps the irs off your trail.
我也知道
I know that,too.
最後一筆是證實死亡後給的
So,the final payment must be for proof of death.
也就是殺次人5萬塊錢
That makes $50,000 the price of a kill.
一年內他共進行了3次這樣的轉帳
He did that 3 times over a period of 12 months, but 2 days ago,
但兩天前 他直接一次轉了10萬
he raided his account for $100,000 all in one hit.
他還註銷了所有帳戶 並把全部財產捐給受害者支持組織
He also closed all his accounts and handed his entire estate over to a victims support group.
有人不願意咱高科技搗亂 把我們踢出來了
Someone who isn't suffering from too many brainiacs in the hightech kitchen just bounced us out.
很好 謝謝
Good job.
計算無誤的話 名單上還有兩人 沒錯
If our calculations are correct, there are 2 more names on that list. There are.
名單上每個人都應受到公正審判
Every single person on that list deserves justice.
他說"應受"而不是"受到"
He said deserves, not deserved.
看這 他第二次查看時間
Now look. Right there. He looked at his watch for the second time.
他等的事就要發生了
Whatever he's waiting for is about to happen.
我覺得你一點都不瞭解Emma
I don't think you knew emma at all.
至少不是我所認識的那個
At least not the one I knew.
我編借口跟自己說 她的葬禮不會歡迎我
I made an excuse for myself that I wouldn't be welcome at her funeral.
事實上是我無法面對現實
But the truth is, I couldn't face it.
你認識Emma也改變不了什麼
You knowing emma changes nothing.
但的確改變了
Oh,but it does.
Emma改變了所有她認識的人的生活
Emma changed the lives of everyone she knew.
但至少我和Ray正視了她的死亡
But at least ray and I saw her death for what it truly was
一場慘烈的車禍
a tragic accident.
Dan Patton酒後駕車
Dan patton was drunk.
他殺了Emma 就像對她開槍一樣
He murdered emma,as surely as if he put a gun to her head.
所以他照片不在這?
Is that why his photo's not here?
留著他壓軸登場?
You're saving the best for last?
我們得馬上弄清Dan Patton在哪
We need to locate dan patton now.
10萬塊 附加的摧殘一定不輕
The 100,000 must be for some serious extras.
你還打算殺多少人?
How many other people have you targeted?
我要真話
I want the truth.
我該說的都說完了
I have nothing more to say.
我還有話要說
Oh,but I do.
幾年前在曼哈頓一家旅館 我偶然遇到Emma
I ran into emma, by chance, a few years ago, at a hotel in manhattan.
當時我在辦案 她也是
I was working on a case,so was she.
我知道她已經結婚了
I knew she was married.
但是我不在乎
But I didn't care.
她...她不會的
She... She wouldn't.
不 Emma不會這麼對我的
No. Emma would not do that to me.
你撒謊 是嗎?
You're lying.
告訴我實情 你先說
I want the truth. You first.
Dan Patton是最後一個 沒有別人了
Dan patton is the last one. There are no more.
快告訴我實情
Now,tell me the truth.
那晚在曼哈頓 她對我說 我們如此"一拍即合"
That night in manhattan, she told me our connection was so strong,
僅僅一次太可惜了
it could never happen only once.
我當然樂意奉陪
And I was fine with that.
求你 不要 我身無分文
Please. Please don't. I have nothing, no money,nothing.Nothing
求你別殺我 這跟錢沒關係
please, please don't kill me. This isn't about money.
是因為你害死了Emma Schuller
This is about the murder of emma schuller.
Emma? 天啊 那完全是意外 求你了
Emma? Oh,god. Emmathat wasthat was an accident. Please.
是意外 求你別...
No,that was an accident.Pleaseplease don't
至少
at least...
你看到了你同事的真面目
You now know what kind of man you're working with.
那你的真面目又是什麼 法官?
What kind of man are you,judge?
我已經看夠了罪惡之事逃脫制裁
I've had enough of seeing the guilty walk free of their sins.
那你犯下的罪惡呢?
But what about your sins?
癌癥就是對我的制裁
I got cancer for mine.
也許他還在工作
Maybe he's still at work.
公司說他請假了
Workplace said he left for the day.
Dan Patton 我們是FBI
Dan patton, this is the fbi.
安全!
Clear!
一槍在心臟 一槍在頭部
One to the heart, one to the head.
知道兇手了吧
We know who did it.
Bosola無法離開長島的
Bosola has no way of getting off long island.
他們要轉移Schuller法官 什麼?
They're moving judge schuller. What?
他是高等法院法官  於是案子成了聯邦案件
He's a high court judge. It makes it a federal case now.
如果Bosola根本無意離開長島呢?
What if bosola has no intention of leaving the island?
Garcia說法官拿出了全部資產?
Garcia said the judge was giving his whole estate away?
所有房產和資金
His property,his money.
他註銷了所有賬戶 付清了水電費
He closed out his accounts and paid off his utility bills.
雖然得了癌癥 但他還有6個月時間
He has cancer,but he still has 6 months to live.
為什麼現在就付清所有賬單?
Is there a reason he's paying off all his bills now?
況且他最後那筆10萬塊付款 是殺兩個人的
Not to mention the 100,000 he made as a last and final payment for not one,
不是一個
but 2 kills.
以前他都是先確認目標死亡 再付最後一筆酬勞
Usually the judge waits for confirmation of death before making final payment.
這次他知道自己等不到了
Only this time he knew he wouldn't be around to see it.
他來了! 他在那
Here he comes! Oh,there he is.
Schuller法官!
Judge schuller!
Schuller法官在協助我們 調查一起聯邦案件
Judge schuller is helping us with a federal investigation.
等等 我聽不見 大點聲
Wait a minute. What? I can't hear you. Speak up.
Schuller法官 請問這是否與 最近的一連串謀殺案相關?
Judge schuller,does this have anything to do with the recent rash of murders?
我堅信 正義已經得到伸張
I am of the belief that justice has been served.
Hotch 慢點 什麼?
Hotch, wait a minute. What?
無可奉告 Schuller法官 你如何回應有報道說...
No comment. Judge schuller, can you confirm reports...
我騙了你 什麼?
I lied. What?
你與本案有什麼關係?
Your status in this case?
趴下! 快趴下! 別動!
Everybody down! Get on the ground! Down on the ground! Stay down!
趴下!
Get down!
她對你意義重大
She was special to you.
我在想...
I was just thinking...
初識Emma 我就深知 她會是我今生摯愛
When I first met emma, I knew I would love her for the rest of my life.
那年我們12歲
We were 12 years old.
她常說我們注定是對苦命鴛鴦
She always said we were doomed to be starcrossed lovers,
只能惜嘆有緣無分
destined to wonder what might have been.
我從沒碰過她
I never slept with her, you know.
我對Schuller說的是假話
That wasn't true what I said to schuller.
為了激怒他 打垮他
That was just to get under his skin, knock him off his game.
我明白
I understand.
當初真該娶了她
I should have married her,though.
我離開海軍陸戰隊 就被招進了局
When I left the marines, I was recruited by the bureau,
負責了幾年黑幫團伙案子
spent a few years on the streets,
參與建立了BAU
got involved with starting the bau.
還未曾留心 人生就已匆匆過半
And before I knew it, a lifetime had gone by.
我知道
I hear you.
我錯過與Emma共度餘生的機會
I missed a life with emma because I became obsessed with the chase.
全因沉淪於追兇破案
With the hunt.
Dave 他威脅到了我的家人
Dave,he's threatening my family.
我們會抓到Foyet的 Aaron
And we'll get foyet,aaron.
那你是想說什麼?
Then what's your point?
你還有家庭
You have a family.
當一切了結 你要怎麼做...
When all this is over, what are you gonna do...
才不至於淪落到孑然一身
To make sure you're not a lonely guy wondering why
悔恨為何放走人生中...
you let the purest thing in your life...
最真摯純淨的感情?
Get away?
去哪兒啊?
Going somewhere?
聽過這笑話嗎 兩個愛爾蘭人...
Hear the joke about the two irishmen
聽過 就沒覺得好笑過
yeah,i heard it.Didn't find it funny the first time.
"仁慈之樹總比嚴刑律法更碩果纍纍"
"i have always found that mercy bears richer fruit than strict justice."
亞伯拉罕·林肯
Abraham lincoln.
犯罪心理 第五季 第3集 清算
== 結束 ==
Criminal Minds Season06 Episode03 Reckoner